<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alberto Muñoz-Rueda | Fisioclima</title>
    <link>/author/alberto-mu%C3%B1oz-rueda/</link>
      <atom:link href="/author/alberto-mu%C3%B1oz-rueda/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Alberto Muñoz-Rueda</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/author/alberto-mu%C3%B1oz-rueda/avatar_hu52a603635ecebd45650b162dadabb4e5_12861_270x270_fill_q75_lanczos_center.jpg</url>
      <title>Alberto Muñoz-Rueda</title>
      <link>/author/alberto-mu%C3%B1oz-rueda/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinantes bioquímicos y fisiológicos de la producción y la calidad de la cebada de uso maltero –un reto ante las condiciones climáticas futuras–</title>
      <link>/project/2017-2018_cebadas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2017-2018_cebadas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agricultural production is strongly influenced by climate, and any change in climate can reduce crop productivity and put the food security of the world&amp;rsquo;s growing population at risk. Barley is one of the most important cereal species worldwide in terms of production, being used both in animal and human food as well as in the malting industry. Climate predictions suggest a continuous increase in CO2 in the atmosphere, associated with higher temperatures and an increase in the duration and intensity of droughts. This implies that crop productivity will be affected by complex environmental interactions between these factors (higher [CO2], higher temperature and drought).
In this sense, understanding which biochemical and physiological processes are involved in the interactions of drought, high temperature and high CO2 and knowing through what mechanisms affect growth, final production and grain quality is important if we want to select cultivars of barley that are well adapted to future climatic conditions, maintaining, if possible, production and quality.
This area of research is important due to its potential applications in fields such as the agricultural and food industries. Studies are being carried out where biochemical and physiological characters related with increased tolerance capacity of the crops in the climatic conditions foreseen for the future are selected; However, the influence of these characters on the final production is not so studied, much less their influence on the quality of the grain. On the other hand, studies where the three factors are combined (high CO2, high temperature and drought) are not very abundant and, therefore, we cannot predict how plants will develop under future conditions. That is, we do not know if the mechanisms that allow the plant to benefit from the fertilizing effect of the high CO2 will be valid under the conditions combined with the high temperatures and drought expected.
Therefore, the main objective of this research project is to determine which biochemical and physiological processes are involved in the interaction of combined conditions of high CO2, high temperature and drought, and to know through what mechanisms affect the growth, production and quality of the grain of two cultivars of barley. The key to this proposal is that the study will be multiscalar (physiological and molecular agronomic parameters) and multifactorial (high Tª, high CO2 and drought) which will allow a deep analysis of the interactions that will occur in future climatic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Evaluación de la presencia de hongos micotoxigénicos del género Alternaria en alimentos animales y humanos producidos en la CAPV.</title>
      <link>/project/2021_evaluaci%C3%B3ndelapresenciahongosmicotoxig%C3%A9nicos/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2021_evaluaci%C3%B3ndelapresenciahongosmicotoxig%C3%A9nicos/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Alternaria is a very common fungal genus, including numerous saprophytic, endophytic, and pathogenic species widely distributed in soil and decaying organic matter. It includes pathogenic species that can invade vegetable crops before and after harvesting and is responsible for considerable economic losses, due to the fact that it reduces the yield of the crops and produces alterations in the vegetables during their storage. Species of the genus Alternaria synthesize more than 70 secondary metabolites toxic to plants (phytotoxins), some of which also affect people and animals, which is why they are considered mycotoxins. The main mycotoxins produced by the main toxigenic species of the genus Alternaria do not depend on the host species, and are altenuene(ALT), alternariol (AOH), alternariol monomethyl ether (AME), tenuazonic acid (TeA) and tentoxin (TEN). It is important to note that mycotoxin synthesis depends both on the presence of the producing Alternaria species and on environmental conditions.
Exposure to the toxins of Alternaria spp. it has been linked to the occurrence of adverse health effects in humans and animals and, in many cases, has been shown to have genotoxic, mutagenic, carcinogenic and cytotoxic effects. The mycotoxins of Alternaria spp. have been isolated from fruits (apple, pear, melon, apricot, grapes, raisins, strawberry, olive, citrus and dried figs), vegetables (tomato, pepper and carrot) and tubers (potato), as well as from numerous processed foods with contaminated raw materials (juices, preserves, sauces, etc.). Therefore, the objective of this project is to evaluate the presence of mycotoxigenic fungi of the genus Alternaria and the production of their mycotoxins in foods of plant cultivated in the Basque Country.
We will provide data to prepare a risk analysis of Alternaria mycotoxins in different foods consumed in the Basque Country.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will define which foods for human consumption are those with the highest risk of containing Alternaria and its mycotoxins.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will establish the environmental conditions (seasonal risk) where the appearance of Alternaria and its mycotoxins is minimum and maximum.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We will define the guidelines for storage and handling of food to reduce the presence of Alternaria and its mycotoxins&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quinoa- ¿Opción de cultivo en Álava? Búsqueda de variedades productivas y de alta calidad bajo condiciones climáticas actuales y futuras</title>
      <link>/project/2018-2019_quinoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2018-2019_quinoa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate change supposes an alteration of the main environmental factors that affect the productivity and quality of crops that, together with the increase in food demand by the world&amp;rsquo;s largest population, puts future food security in risk. The scenarios predict an increase in atmospheric CO2, a higher temperature and an increase in the intensity and duration of droughts, which will imply changes in productivity and quality. An alternative is the search for species more tolerant to these environmental stresses, quinoa being one of the possible species, thanks to its high tolerance to drought and salinity. In addition, it is necessary to reduce the use of organic and phosphorous fertilizers in order to reduce the environmental impact of both the contamination of fresh water reserves and the greenhouse gas emissions associated with the fertilizer manufacturing process. For this, it is very important to promote ecological agricultural practices. In this sense, quinoa can also be a very interesting species to be cultivated through ecological agricultural practices since the demand is increasing due to its high nutritional value, higher than that of cereals with gluten; especially because of its high protein content (approximately 16%), its excellent digestibility (92%) and balanced content of essential amino acids, such as lysine and methionine, characteristics highly appreciated by groups committed to the environment and health.
Although various studies are being carried out on its adaptation to different regions, there is still a long way to go to find the right variety, cycle and cultivation needs. Therefore, the objective of this research project will be, from a multiscalar analysis, on the one hand, to verify the degree of adaptation in the Alava plain of different quinoa cultivars and, on the other hand, to study the incidence of drought in production and grain quality in field studies using ecological agricultural practices.
The approach will range from production studies to molecular and biochemical analyzes, allowing the interrelation between different study scales and obtaining results of both basic and applied knowledge, with the aim of maintaining food security in future climatic conditions and under premises of sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
