<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Climate Change | Fisioclima</title>
    <link>/tag/climate-change/</link>
      <atom:link href="/tag/climate-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Climate Change</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>/images/logo_hu3fcfe40a2b605561f55cc8be1a2377c0_94697_300x300_fit_lanczos_2.png</url>
      <title>Climate Change</title>
      <link>/tag/climate-change/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Determinantes bioquímicos y fisiológicos de la producción y la calidad de la cebada de uso maltero –un reto ante las condiciones climáticas futuras–</title>
      <link>/project/2017-2018_cebadas/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2017-2018_cebadas/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Agricultural production is strongly influenced by climate, and any change in climate can reduce crop productivity and put the food security of the world&amp;rsquo;s growing population at risk. Barley is one of the most important cereal species worldwide in terms of production, being used both in animal and human food as well as in the malting industry. Climate predictions suggest a continuous increase in CO2 in the atmosphere, associated with higher temperatures and an increase in the duration and intensity of droughts. This implies that crop productivity will be affected by complex environmental interactions between these factors (higher [CO2], higher temperature and drought).
In this sense, understanding which biochemical and physiological processes are involved in the interactions of drought, high temperature and high CO2 and knowing through what mechanisms affect growth, final production and grain quality is important if we want to select cultivars of barley that are well adapted to future climatic conditions, maintaining, if possible, production and quality.
This area of research is important due to its potential applications in fields such as the agricultural and food industries. Studies are being carried out where biochemical and physiological characters related with increased tolerance capacity of the crops in the climatic conditions foreseen for the future are selected; However, the influence of these characters on the final production is not so studied, much less their influence on the quality of the grain. On the other hand, studies where the three factors are combined (high CO2, high temperature and drought) are not very abundant and, therefore, we cannot predict how plants will develop under future conditions. That is, we do not know if the mechanisms that allow the plant to benefit from the fertilizing effect of the high CO2 will be valid under the conditions combined with the high temperatures and drought expected.
Therefore, the main objective of this research project is to determine which biochemical and physiological processes are involved in the interaction of combined conditions of high CO2, high temperature and drought, and to know through what mechanisms affect the growth, production and quality of the grain of two cultivars of barley. The key to this proposal is that the study will be multiscalar (physiological and molecular agronomic parameters) and multifactorial (high Tª, high CO2 and drought) which will allow a deep analysis of the interactions that will occur in future climatic conditions.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Quinoa- ¿Opción de cultivo en Álava? Búsqueda de variedades productivas y de alta calidad bajo condiciones climáticas actuales y futuras</title>
      <link>/project/2018-2019_quinoa/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2018-2019_quinoa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Climate change supposes an alteration of the main environmental factors that affect the productivity and quality of crops that, together with the increase in food demand by the world&amp;rsquo;s largest population, puts future food security in risk. The scenarios predict an increase in atmospheric CO2, a higher temperature and an increase in the intensity and duration of droughts, which will imply changes in productivity and quality. An alternative is the search for species more tolerant to these environmental stresses, quinoa being one of the possible species, thanks to its high tolerance to drought and salinity. In addition, it is necessary to reduce the use of organic and phosphorous fertilizers in order to reduce the environmental impact of both the contamination of fresh water reserves and the greenhouse gas emissions associated with the fertilizer manufacturing process. For this, it is very important to promote ecological agricultural practices. In this sense, quinoa can also be a very interesting species to be cultivated through ecological agricultural practices since the demand is increasing due to its high nutritional value, higher than that of cereals with gluten; especially because of its high protein content (approximately 16%), its excellent digestibility (92%) and balanced content of essential amino acids, such as lysine and methionine, characteristics highly appreciated by groups committed to the environment and health.
Although various studies are being carried out on its adaptation to different regions, there is still a long way to go to find the right variety, cycle and cultivation needs. Therefore, the objective of this research project will be, from a multiscalar analysis, on the one hand, to verify the degree of adaptation in the Alava plain of different quinoa cultivars and, on the other hand, to study the incidence of drought in production and grain quality in field studies using ecological agricultural practices.
The approach will range from production studies to molecular and biochemical analyzes, allowing the interrelation between different study scales and obtaining results of both basic and applied knowledge, with the aim of maintaining food security in future climatic conditions and under premises of sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Reconciling water-use efficiency estimates across scales under future climate change scenarios using PHLoem carbon ISotopic</title>
      <link>/project/2020-2023_phlisco/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Mar 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>/project/2020-2023_phlisco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The exchange of water for carbon between the vegetation and the atmosphere constitutes the most important feedback mechanism underlying the regulation of water and carbon (C) cycles by the terrestrial biosphere. Water use efficiency (WUE) is the trait that serves to describe this intimate link between the C and water cycles and is a crucial parameter incorporated in many land-surface-models to predict vegetation-climatic feedbacks under future climate change scenario. WUE can be estimated using multiple approaches and methodologies concerning different temporal spatial and temporal scales. Empirical comparison of WUE estimates reveal that important disagreements exists among methodologies; however, these empirical comparisons cannot reveal the underlying mechanisms driving these discrepancies. Two of the most widely used methodologies to estimate WUE are measurements of the ratio of photosynthesis to stomatal conductance to water, using gas-exchange techniques, and analyses of the carbon isotopic composition (d13C) of plant material. This latter approach is based on the assumption that the d13C of plant material is mostly the result of isotopic discrimination occurring during diffusion through the stomatal pores and fractionation at the point of carboxylation. The vast majority of these studies analyses d13C in either the leaves or the wood, but these reflect the signal of the plant physiological status all along the organ ontogeny. In addition, in tall trees, d13C varies greatly among leaves and thus individual measurements cannot capture whole-tree physiological status. Analyses of the phloem d13C constitute a promising avenue, as the phloem signal, when collected at the base of the trunk should reflect the whole tree physiological performance. Still, WUE estimates from d13C, even when they come from the phloem, are usually lower than WUE from measurements of gas-exchange. This is partly due the fact that estimates of WUE from d13C most often neglect the leaf internal resistance to CO2 diffusion, beyond the stomatal pores. Mesophyll conductance (gm) is the inverse of this resistance and it is a trait that varies greatly among plant functional types and in large individuals (adult trees) also among canopy layers. Furthermore, gm also varies greatly in response to climate change drivers including increasing vapour pressure deficit, water availability and atmospheric CO2concentration. Previous studies, including ours, combining measurements of gm with WUE from different estimates suggest that neglecting gm limitations in the calculations of WUE from d13C could induce large biases and that these biases would be even larger under water limitations.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Still, these studies showed that even after incorporating gm limitations, other post-photosynthetic fractionation processes exist that underlie disagreements between WUE estimates. The aim of this proposal is to reconcile estimates of WUE describing vegetation functioning at different scales by incorporating internal leaf diffusional limitations, using Fagus sylvatica as a model species. This objective will materialise in the form of a novel protocol for estimating whole-tree WUE at large spatial scales from analyses of the phloem content. In this project, we will combine measurements under controlled conditions, intensive field measurements of physiological performance, sampling of physiological performance (including WUE from different methodolgies and gm) across a broad geographical range.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
